夏洛克!
Sherlock!
(夏洛克·福尔摩斯)
不过是个戏法
It's a trick.
变戏法而已
Just a magic trick.
不 行了 别说了
No. All right, stop it now.
等等 就站在原处
Now, stay exactly where you are.
- 别动  - 好
- Don't move.  - All right.
一直盯着我
Keep your eyes fixed on me.
拜托了 你会为我这么做吗?
Please, would you do this for me?
做什么?
Do what?
这通电话...
This phone call, it's er...
是我的遗言
it's my note.
人们都这么做 不是吗?
It's what people do, don't they?
留个遗言
Leave a note.
留遗言干什么?
Leave a note when?
永别了 约翰
Goodbye, John.
不 别...
No. Don't...
夏洛克!
Sherlock!
约翰
John.
约翰 看着我 看着我
John, look at me. Look at me.
睡
And sleep.
睡沉点 再沉点 直接睡着
Right the way down, right the way deep, right the way, sound asleep.
这就对了
That's real.
很好 只有我的声音在你的脑海深处
That's good, with my voice just there in the centre of your head
将你环绕
and floating all the way around you.
然后我数三 二 一...
And you will awaken in three, two, one...
醒
zero.
请让我过去! 他是我的朋友
Let me come through please! He's my friend.
胡扯!
Bollocks!
不 不 太显而易见了
No, no, no, no, it's obvious.
就是这个手法 太明显了
That's how he did it. It's obvious.
你以为他是达伦·布朗(英国著名魔术师)啊? 别扯了 夏洛克死了
Derren Brown? Let it go, Sherlock's dead.
当真如此吗?
But is he?
尸体都有了 就是他
There was a body, it was him.
肯定是他 茉莉·琥珀验的尸
It was definitely him, Molly Hooper laid him out.
不 她在撒谎
No, she's lying.
那是带着人皮面具的吉姆·莫里亚蒂的尸体
It was Jim Moriarty's body with a mask on.
面具?
A mask?
区区一根蹦极绳 一副面具 还有达伦·布朗
A bungee rope, a mask, Derren Brown.
两年了 你的想法越发邪门歪道了
Two years and the theories keep getting more stupid.
你今天还要跟我讲多少?
How many more have you got for me today?
要知道那边整个区域的地砖
Well, you know the paving slabs in that whole area,
即便是他砸到的那几块
even the exact ones that he landed on,
- 它们都...  - 负罪感!
- you know they were all...  - Guilt!
是一切的根源
That's all this is.
是你和多诺万让我们大家
You pushed us all into thinking
都认为夏洛克是个骗子的
that Sherlock that was a fraud, you and Donovan.
你害死了他 但他不会再活过来了
You did this and it killed him and he's staying dead.
你真的以为你编出的荒唐故事够多
Do you honestly believe that if you have enough stupid theories,
就能改变既有的事实吗?
it's going to change what really happened?
我相信夏洛克·福尔摩斯
I believe in Sherlock Holmes.
是啊 既便如此 他也回不来了
Yeah, well, that won't bring him back.
经过警方的广泛调查证实...
And that after extensive police investigations...
理查德·布鲁克的确是詹姆斯·莫里亚蒂捏造的人物...
Richard Brook did indeed prove to be the creation of James Moriarty...
当夏洛克·福尔摩斯被洗清一切罪名和嫌疑时
Amidst unprecedented scenes, there was uproar in court
全庭爆发出史无前例的欢呼
as Sherlock Holmes was vindicated and cleared of all suspicion.
很不幸 对于这位两年前
Sadly, all this comes too late for the detective,
名噪一时的侦探 一切为时已晚
who became something of a celebrity two years ago.
现在警方面临的质疑是 为何当时任由事态发展至此
Questions are now being asked as to why police let matters get so far.
夏洛克·福尔摩斯从伦敦巴茨医院楼顶
Sherlock Holmes fell to his death
坠落致死 尽管未曾留下遗言
from the top of London's Bart's Hospital. Although he left no note,
他的朋友称他不太可能应付...
friends say it's unlikely he was able to cope with the...
好吧 昔日友人不再
Well then. Absent friends.
敬夏洛克
Sherlock.
愿他的灵魂安息
And may God rest his soul.
你闯进来是有目的的
只要老实交待 就让你安稳睡去
还记得睡觉是什么滋味吗?
什么?
他说什么?
他说我过去为海军效力...
在那有过一段悲伤情史
什么?
What?
我浴室里的电路坏了...
我老婆和隔壁邻居上床了
造棺材的...
还有...
我若现在回家...
便可捉奸在床
我就知道!
我就知道他们俩有一腿
好了 这位朋友
现在这里只有你和我了
为了找你真是花了我一番功夫
仔细听我说
Now listen to me.
现在伦敦活跃着一个地下恐怖组织
There's an underground terrorist network active in London
他们策划了一场大型恐怖袭击
and a massive attack is imminent.
抱歉 假期结束了...
Sorry, but the holiday is over...
我的老弟
brother dear.
回贝克街去吧...
Back to Baker Street...
夏洛克·福尔摩斯
Sherlock Holmes.
《神探夏洛克》
《空灵柩》
赏点钱吧?
Penny for the guy?
先生 赏点钱吧?
Oi, mate, penny for the guy?
赏点钱吧 先生? 赏点钱吧?
Penny for the guy, mate? Penny for the guy?
赏点钱吧? 赏点钱吧?
Penny for the guy? Penny for the guy?
真是我做过最荒唐的事情
That was the most ridiculous thing I've ever done.
你还入侵了阿富汗呢
You invaded Afghanistan.
(骷髅谜案)
你倒是没闲着 是吧?
You have been busy, haven't you?
- 真是勤劳的小蜜蜂  - 没错
- Quite the busy little bee.  - Hmm.
我花了两年时间 才捣毁了莫里亚蒂的犯罪网
Moriarty's network. Took me two years to dismantle it.
你确定消灭干净了?
And you're confident you have?
塞尔维亚那边是整个拼图的最后一块了
The Serbian side was the last piece of the puzzle.
没错 你在莫佩尔蒂男爵的案子里牵涉挺深
Yes. You got yourself in deep there with Baron Maupertuis.
- 好大一个阴谋  - 那是相当得大
- Quite a scheme.  - Colossal.
无论如何 你现在安全了
Anyway. You're safe now.
嗯
Mmm.
说句"谢谢"死不了的
A small "thank you" wouldn't go amiss.
谢你何用?
What for?
谢我拔刀相助
For wading in.
我得提醒你一下 我一般可不会亲自出马
In case you've forgotten, field work is not my natural milieu.
"拔刀相助"?
"Wading in"?
你就坐在那儿眼看着我被打成肉酱
You sat there and watched me being beaten a pulp.
- 我助你脱身了  - 不 是我自救的
- I got you out.  - No, I got me out.
你干嘛不早点发话?
Why didn't you intervene sooner?
我总不能暴露自己吧?
I couldn't risk giving myself away, could I?
- 一切都会前功尽弃的  - 你看得很开心
- It would have ruined everything.  - You were enjoying it.
- 胡扯  - 绝对很开心
- Nonsense.  - Definitely enjoying it.
听着 夏洛克 你知道当卧底
Listen, do you have any idea what it was like, Sherlock,
是什么概念吗?
going undercover?
在他们那种人当中潜伏?
Smuggling my way into their ranks like that?
吵得要死 那么多人!
The noise, the people!
我都不知道你还会塞尔维亚语呢
I didn't know you spoke Serbian.
之前是不会 但塞尔维亚语来源于斯拉夫语
I didn't. But the language has a Slavic root.
有很多来自土耳其语和德语的外来词
Frequent Turkish and German loan words.
花了我几个小时学会的
Took me a couple of hours.
嗯 风采不比当年了啊
Hmm, you're slipping.
中年人了 我的老弟
Middle-age, brother mine.
谁也逃不掉的
Comes to us all.
不 你不加糖的 对吧?
Oh, no, you don't take it, do you?
- 不加  - 连这种小事都会忘记
- No.  - You forget a little thing like that.
是啊
Yes.
看起来你还忘了不少小事
You forget lots of little things, it seems.
没错
Uh-huh.
不怎么适合你啊
Not sure about that.
- 嗯?  - 显老了
- Hmm?  - Ages you.
只是尝个新鲜
Just trying it out.
太显老了
Well, it ages you.
听着... 我不是你母亲 我没有什么权利...
Look... I'm not your mother, I've no right to expect it...
- 不...  - 但哪怕一个电话也好啊 约翰!
- No...  - But just one phone call, John!
一个电话报报平安就够了
Just one phone call would have done.
我知道
I know.
- 我们一起经历了那么多!  - 是的
- After all we went through!  - Yes.
我很抱歉
I am sorry.
听着 我理解你心里很难受 在...
Look, I understand how difficult it was for you after...
在那之后...
after...
哈德森太太 我已经放下了过去 都放下了
I just let it slide, Mrs Hudson, I let it all slide.
只是不知为什么 越来越难下定决心拿起电话了
And it just got harder and harder to pick up the phone, somehow.
你懂我的意思吗?
Do you know what I mean?
我要你对这件事重视起来 夏洛克 明白吗?
I need you to give this matter your full attention, Sherlock, is that quite clear?
- 你觉得这衬衣怎么样?  - 夏洛克!
- What do you think of this shirt?  - Sherlock!
我会调查你说的地下恐怖组织 迈克罗夫特
I will find your underground terror cell, Mycroft.
送我回伦敦吧
Just put me back in London.
我想要回到那个熟悉的城市
I need to get to know the place again, breathe it in.
感受它每一次心跳的颤动
Feel every quiver of its beating heart.
我们有一个特工在调查时牺牲了
One of our men died getting this information.
各种渠道的消息都一致证明
All the chatter, all the traffic concurs,
伦敦将会遭受大规模恐怖袭击
there's going to be a terrorist strike on London, a big one.
约翰·华生怎么样了?
And what about John Watson?
- 约翰?  - 对 你见过他吗?
- John?  - Mm. Have you seen him?
当然 我们每周五还一起去吃炸鱼薯呢
Oh, yes, we meet up every Friday for fish and chips.
我当然一直在留意他
I've kept a weather eye on him, of course.
你回来的事... 我们还没有告诉他
We haven't been in touch at all to... prepare him.
算了
No.
我们要解决掉这东西
Well, we'll have to get rid of that.
- 我们?  - 太显老了
- We?  - He looks ancient.
我不想别人看见我和一个老头在一起
I can't be seen to be wandering around with an old man.
我都不敢把房子租出去
I couldn't face letting it out.
他从不让我打扫灰尘
He never liked me dusting.
我知道
No, I know.
那现在呢? 你怎么改变主意了?
So why now? What changed your mind?
有件事我想告诉你
Well, I've got some news.
天啊 不会吧?
Oh, God, is it serious?
什么? 不 不 我没病
What? No, no, I'm not ill.
我很好 我要...
I've, well, I'm...
开始新生活了
moving on.
你要离开这里了?
You're emigrating?
不 嗯 不对 我...
Nope. Er, no, I've er...
我遇见了某个人
I have met someone.
噢! 太棒了
Oh! Ah, lovely.
是 我们要结婚了 我要去求婚了
Yeah. We're getting married. Well, I'm going to ask, anyway.
夏洛克刚去世没多久呀?
So soon after Sherlock?
嗯 是啊
Hmm, well, yes.
他叫什么?
What's his name?
是个女的
It's a woman.
- 女的?  - 是啊 当然是女的
- A woman?!  - Yes, of course it's a woman.
- 你真的想通了 是吗?  - 哈德森太太 我说过多少次了?
- You really have moved on, haven't you?  - Mrs Hudson, how many times?
夏洛克不是我的男朋友!
Sherlock was not my boyfriend!
与人和平共存 这是我的座右铭
Live and let live, that's my motto.
听着 我不是同性恋!
Listen to me. I am not gay!
我想给约翰一个惊喜 他会很高兴的
I think I'll surprise John. He'll be delighted.
你这么觉得?
You think so?
嗯 突然出现在贝克街上 比如从蛋糕里突然跳出来
Mm, pop into Baker Street, who knows, jump out of a cake.
贝克街? 他早就已经不在那里了
Baker Street? He isn't there any more.
他为什么还留在那? 已经过去两年了
Why would he be? It's been two years.
他已经有了自己的生活
He's got on with his life.
我都不在 他生活个毛啊
What life? I've been away.
他今晚会去哪?
Where's he going to be tonight?
- 我怎么知道?  - 你一直知道
- How would I know?  - You always know.
他今晚在马里波恩路上订了一家餐厅的位子
He has a dinner reservation in the Marylebone Road.
那家店不错
Nice little spot.
他们家有几瓶2000年的圣埃米里翁酒
They have a few bottles of the 2000 Saint-Emilion,
其实我更喜欢2001年的
though I prefer the 2001.
我想我可以顺路去看看
I think maybe I'll just drop by.
你非常有可能不受欢迎
You know, it is just possible that you won't be welcome.
不 不会的
No, it isn't.
- 现在告诉我它在哪?  - 什么在哪?
- Now, where is it?  - Where's what?
你懂的
You know what.
欢迎回来 福尔摩斯先生
Welcome back, Mr Holmes.
谢谢
Thank you.
老哥
Blud.
先生 我能为您服务吗?
Sir, can I help you?
你妻子给你发了短信 可能她快要生了
Your wife just texted you, possibly her contractions have started.
抱歉 先生
Excuse me, sir.
先生 我真的非常抱歉
Oh, sir, I am so, so sorry.
对不起 我这就去厨房帮您把它烘干
Er, please, let me just go to the kitchen and dry that off for you.
您点过菜了 先生? 我帮您收走菜单
Finished with that, sir? Allow me to take it for you.
女士 我建议您看这份菜单 两份一样
Madam, can I suggest you look at this menu, it's completely identical.
需要点菜吗 先生?
Can I help you with anything, sir?
嗨 我想要一瓶香槟酒 要上等的
Hi, yeah, I'm looking for a bottle of champagne. A good one.
嗯 这些都是
Hmm, well, these are all
极好的上等红酒 先生
excellent vintages, sir.
我不擅长点酒
Oh, it's not really my area,
有什么推荐吗?
what do you suggest?
好的 您点的其实也很好
Well, you cannot possibly go wrong,
但如果您喜欢
but if you'd like my personal
- 我个人的推荐的话...  - 嗯?
- recommendation...  - Hmm?
这酒单上的最后一个是我的最爱
This last one on the list is a favourite of mine.
然后你可以说 这酒让我想起了某个故去的朋友
It is, you might in fact say, like a face from the past.
很好 我就要那个了
Great. I'll have that one please.
那种无比熟悉的感觉会让你惊讶!
It is familiar, but with the quality of surprise!
好啊 别让我失望
Well, surprise me.
我肯定让你大吃一惊 先生
I'm certainly endeavouring to, sir.
抱歉让你久等了
Sorry that took so long.
你还好吧?
You OK?
我吗? 挺好 我很好
Yeah, yeah. Me? Fine. I am fine.
你找我来想问什么来着?
Now then, what did you want to ask me?
- 喝点酒吗?  - 不用了 水就好
- More wine?  - No, I'm good with water, thanks.
好
Right.
- 然后呢?  - 嗯 然后...
- So?  - Er, so...
玛丽...
Mary...
听着...
listen, um...
我知道有些突然
I know it hasn't been long,
我知道你我才认识不久...
and I know we haven't known each other for a long time...
- 继续说  - 好 我继续
- Go on.  - Yes, I will.
你知道 过去的几年来我很不容易
As you know, these last couple of years haven't been easy for me.
遇见你...
And meeting you...
遇见你应该是几年来
Yeah, meeting you has been the best thing
最幸运的一件事
that could have possibly happened.
- 我同意  - 什么?
- I agree.  - What?
我同意 遇见我对你来说是最幸运的事
I agree, I'm the best thing that could have happened to you.
- 抱歉  - 啊 不 嗯...
- Sorry.  - Well, no, it's, um...
所以...
So...
要是你和我在一起 玛丽 要是你能看到将来 嗯...
if you'll have me, Mary, could you see your way, um...
要是你觉得有希望...
If you could see your way to...
先生 你会格外喜欢这瓶红酒
Sir, you'll find this vintage exceptionally to your liking.
陈年的味道 新鲜的颜色
It has all the qualities of the old, with the colour of the new.
- 抱歉 先别打岔  - 就像盯着一群陌生人看
- No, sorry, not now, please.  - Like a gaze from a crowd of strangers,
突然在人群中发现一位老朋友
suddenly one is aware of staring into the face of an old friend.
不 听着 你能不能...?
No, look, seriously, could you just...?
你穿燕尾服真是奇怪
Interesting thing, a tuxedo.
对朋友很关切 对服务生却毫不注意
Lends distinction to friends and anonymity to waiters.
约翰?
John?
约翰 怎么了? 怎么?
John, what is it? What?
好吧 长话短说...
Well, the short version...
我没死
not dead.
这样刺激你是我不好 我知道
Bit mean springing it on you like that, I know.
可能会让你犯心脏病 可能现在还会
Could have given you a heart attack, probably still will.
但我的解释是 给你一个惊喜挺好玩
But in my defence, it was very funny.
好吧 可能解释得不好
OK, it's not a great defence.
- 噢 不 你是...  - 对 是我
- Oh, no, you're...  - Oh, yes.
天啊!
Oh, my God!
- 没那么严重  - 你死了 你从楼上跳了下来
- Not quite.  - You died, you jumped off a roof.
- 没有  - 你死了
- No.  - You're dead.
没有 我很确定 我自查过了 抱歉
No, I'm quite sure, I checked. Excuse me.
你的... 也能擦掉吗?
Does... does yours rub off too?
天啊! 天啊!
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
你知道你都做了什么吗?!
Do you have any idea what you've done?!
好吧 约翰 我突然意识到我可能
OK, John, I'm suddenly realising I probably owe you
欠你一个道歉...
some sort of an apology...
好了 约翰 不要...
All right, just, John, just keep...
两年了
Two years.
两年啊! 嗯?
Two years! Hmm?
我以为...
I thought...
我还以为...
你死了
you were dead.
嗯?
Hmm?
我为了你伤心欲绝
Now, you let me grieve. Hmm.
你怎么能这样?
How could you do that?
嗯?!
How?!
等等 在你做出什么会后悔的行为之前
Wait, before you do anything that you might regret, um,
先让我问个问题 就一个
one question, just let me ask one question.
你真的不打算刮了嘴上那玩意儿吗?
Are you really going to keep that?
我曾计算过 邀请莫里亚蒂
I calculated that there were 13 possibilities
上屋顶的可能性有13种
once I'd invited Moriarty onto the roof.
我希望在任何一种可能性下都能存活
I wanted to avoid dying, if at all possible.
方案一 将自己弹射至一辆装满洗衣袋的货车上
The first scenario involved hurling myself into a parked van filled with washing bags.
不可行 角度太陡
Impossible, the angle was too steep.
作为一个天才 你有时真是蠢得惊人
You know, for a genius, you can be remarkably thick.
- 什么?  - 我不在乎你是怎么伪造死亡的 夏洛克
- What?  - I don't care how you faked it, Sherlock.
我想知道为什么
I want to know why.
为什么? 因为我必须阻止莫里亚蒂
Why? Because Moriarty had to be stopped.
哦
Oh.
你说的是...?
Why, as in...?
明白了 为什么?
I see. Yes. Why?
这解释起来有点困难
That's a little more difficult to explain.
我有整个晚上的时间
I've got all night.
事实上 呃 这基本是迈克罗夫特的主意
Actually, um, that was mostly Mycroft's idea.
哦 所以这是你哥哥的计划?
Oh, so it was your brother's plan?
可他还需要一个女性密友协助
Oh, but he would have needed a confidante.
嗯
Mm-hm.
抱歉
Sorry.
所以他是唯一知情的? 只有他一个?
But he was the only one? The only one who knew?
还有些其他人 无法避免 这是个复杂的计划
A couple of others. It was a very elaborate plan, it had to be.
- 13种可能性中接下来的是...  - 还有谁?
- The next of the 13 possibilities was...  - Who else?
还有谁知道?
Who else knew?
- 谁?!  - 茉莉
- Who?!  - Molly.
- 茉莉?!  - 茉莉·琥珀
- Molly?!  - Molly Hooper
- 还有我认识的一些流浪者 就这些了  - 很好
- and some of my homeless network and that's all.  - OK.
很好
OK.
只有你哥哥 茉莉·琥珀 以及100个流浪汉
So just your brother, Molly Hooper and 100 tramps.
哈 怎么可能! 也就25个
Ha, no! 25 at most.
说实在的 你没开玩笑吧? 真打算留着这胡子?
Seriously, it's not a joke? You're really keeping this?
咳 是的
Er, yeah.
当真?
Sure?
玛丽喜欢它
Mary likes it.
嗯哼 不 她不喜欢
Hmm, no, she doesn't.
- 她喜欢  - 她不喜欢
- She does.  - She doesn't.
哦 别这样
Oh, don't.
- 哈 棒极了!  - 听着 我很抱歉 真的很抱歉
- Oh, brilliant!  - Look, I'm sorry, I'm sorry,
我不知道该怎么告诉你...
I didn't know how to tell you...
很好 不不 没关系 我连这个都没注意到呢!
Right, no, no, this is charming. I've really missed this!
就一句话 夏洛克 我就只需要一句话而已!
One word, Sherlock, that is all I would have needed!
就一句话告诉我你还活着!
One word to let me know that you were alive!
我好几次差点想联系你 可...
I've nearly been in contact so many times, but...
- 我担心你会不小心透露真相  - 什么?
- I worried that, you know, you might say something indiscreet.  - What?
- 事态会一团糟 好比出袋之猫  - 所以这成了我的错!
- You know, let the cat out of the bag.  - So this is my fault!
天哪! 为什么只有我觉得这是错的?
Oh, God! Why am I the only one who thinks that this is wrong?!
为什么只有我表现得像个正常人!
The only one reacting like a human being!
- 反应过度  - 没错 反应过度!
- Over-reacting.  - Over-reacting!
- 约翰!  - 就是反应过度! 你伪造了自己的死亡
- John!  - Over-reacting! So you fake your own death and you waltz in here
又大摇大摆走了进来! 可是我一点也不觉得有问题
large as bloody life! Shh. But I'm not meant to have a problem with it,
因为夏洛克·福尔摩斯觉得这一·点·儿也没错!
cos Sherlock Holmes thinks it's a perfectly OK thing to do!
闭嘴! 我不想让任何人知道我还活着!
Shut up! I don't want everyone knowing I'm still alive!
- 哦 所以目前为止这还是个秘密?  - 是的 还是个秘密!
- Oh, so it's still a secret, is it?!  - Yes, it's still a secret!
- 你保证不告诉别人?  - 你发誓!
- Promise you won't tell anyone?  - Swear to God!
伦敦有危险 约翰 一场恐怖袭击即将发生 我需要你的帮助
London is in danger, John. There's an imminent terrorist attack and I need your help.
我的帮助?
My help?
承认吧 你想念这个
You have missed this, admit it.
追逐时的刺激 血管里奔腾的血液
The thrill of the chase, the blood pumping through your veins,
你我二人对抗整个世界
just the two of us against the rest of the world.
我不明白 我说了我很抱歉
I don't understand, I said I'm sorry,
难道不应该这么做吗?
isn't that what you're supposed to do?
老天 你对人的天性一无所知 对吧?
Gosh, you don't know anything about human nature, do you?
唔 天性? 不懂
Hmm, nature? No.
人类? 不懂
Human? No.
我去劝他回来
I'll talk him round.
- 你愿意?  - 哦 是啊
- You will?  - Oh, yeah.
玛丽
Mary.
你敢相信吗 他胆子能大成那样?
Can you believe his nerve?
我喜欢他
I like him.
你说什么?
What?
我喜欢他
I like him.
那玩意儿会让你丧命
Those things will kill you.
哦 你这混蛋!
Oh, you bastard!
是时候回来了
It's time to come back.
你一直在游手好闲啊 格拉汉姆
You've been letting things slide, Graham.
- 是格雷格  - 格雷格
- Greg.  - Greg.
众所周知 在投入大笔反恐预算后...
Very common belief, with an anti terrorism bill...
政府感到有责任
the Government feels duty-bound
尽快推动立法程序的进行...
to push through the legislation with all due exped...
现在 站在原地别动
Now, stay exactly where you are.
你在哪?
Where are you?
别动
Don't move.
一直盯着我
Keep your eyes fixed on me.
什么? 发生什么了? 怎么回事?
What? What's happening? What's going on?
你会为我这么做吗? 拜托了
Please, will you do this for me? Please.
做什么?
Do what?
这通电话...
This phone call...
是我的遗言
it's my note.
人们都这么做 不是吗?
That's what people do, don't they?
留个遗言
Leave a note.
留遗言干什么?
Leave a note when?
- 永别了 约翰  - 不
- Goodbye, John.  - No.
夏洛克!
Sherlock!
啊哈!
Oh, ho!
啥?! 你发神经了吗?!
What?! Are you out of your mind?!
我不明白为什么不行
I don't see why not.
这和你的那些说法一样行得通
It's just as plausible as some of your theories.
听着 劳拉 要是你不打算严肃对待的话...
Look, if you're not going to take it seriously, Laura...
我确实认真对待了
I do take it seriously.
我觉得我们不需要戴帽子
I don't think we should wear hats.
我建立了"空灵柩"社团 让志同道合的人们相聚
I founded "The Empty Hearse" so like-minded people could meet,
推测各种可能!
discuss theories!
夏洛克还活着
Sherlock's still out there.
我确信
I'm convinced of it.
天啊!
Oh, my God!
哦... 我的... 天啊!
Oh... my... God!
(夏洛克·福尔摩斯没死...)
"他的行动悄无声息
"His movements were so silent,
鬼鬼祟祟 就如同
so furtive he reminded me
追踪气息的寻血猎犬"
of a trained bloodhound picking out a scent."
- 如同什么?  - "我忍不住想象 要是他选择用天赋对抗法律
- You what?  - "I couldn't help thinking what an amazing criminal he'd make
- 那他会成为多么厉害的罪犯"  - 别读了
- if he turned his talents against the law."  - Don't read that.
- 著名的博客 总算读到了  - 拜托 这只是...
- Famous blog, finally.  - Come on, that's...
过去的故事 我明白 但它其实并没有过去 不是吗? 因为他...
Ancient history, yes, I know, but it's not though, is it, because he's...
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
洗脸
Having a wash.
你打算刮了它
You're shaving it off.
- 你讨厌它呀  - 是夏洛克讨厌它
- Well, you hate it.  - Sherlock hates it.
- 显然人人都讨厌它  - 好吧!
- Apparently everyone hates it.  - Oh!
- 你还打算见他吗?  - 不 我打算去上班
- Are you going to see him again?  - No, I'm going to work.
- 那下班后 你会再见他吗?  - 不会
- Oh, and after work, are you going to see him again?  - No.
天啊 我被胡子扎了六个月
God, I had six months of bristly kisses for me
然后这家伙一出现...
and then his nibs turns up...
我不是为夏洛克·福尔摩斯刮胡子的
I don't shave for Sherlock Holmes.
你该把这句话印在衬衫上
You should put that on a T-shirt.
- 别说了  - 不然呢?
- Shut up.  - Or what?
不然我娶了你
Or I'll marry you.
伦敦 就像一个污水池
London, it's like a great cesspool into which all kinds
各种各样的罪犯 间谍和流浪者都难以抗拒地沉沦其中
of criminals, agents and drifters are irresistibly drained.
有时关键不是谁沉沦了 而是谁行动了?
Sometimes it's not a question of who, it's a question of who knows?
如果这个人不订报纸了 告诉我
If this man cancels his papers, I need to know.
如果这个女人没把狗安顿好就离开伦敦了
If this woman leaves London without putting her dog into kennels,
告诉我
I need to know.
我盯着一些人 他们是预兆
I have certain people, they are markers.
如果他们开始行动 我就知道要出事了
If they start to move, I'll know something's up.
就像老鼠逃离下沉的船
Like rats deserting a sinking ship.
非常有趣 夏洛克
All very interesting, Sherlock,
但是恐怖警告已经升级为紧急戒备了
but the terror alert has been raised to critical.
没意思 该你了
Boring. Your move.
我们有可靠消息 恐怖袭击将要发生
We have solid information, an attack is coming.
可靠消息 秘密恐怖组织正在计划一场袭击...
Solid information, a secret terrorist organisation is planning an attack...
秘密恐怖组织就是干这个的 不是吗? 这是他们的高尔夫游戏
That's what secret terrorist organisations do, isn't it? It's their version of golf.
- 一位探员为此丧命了  - 这个嘛
- An agent gave his life to tell us that.  - Oh, well,
或许他不该这么做 显然他只是想炫耀一下
perhaps he shouldn't have done. He was obviously just trying to show off.
你的这些"预兆"们都没有异常举动吗?
None of these "markers" of yours is behaving in any way suspiciously?
该你了
Your move.
没有 迈克罗夫特 但你必须相信我 我会找到答案的
No, Mycroft, but you have to trust me. I'll find the answer.
但要等到在线博客上出现一个奇怪的短语
But it'll be in an odd phrase in an on-line blog,
或者一场去乡村的不速之行
or an unexpected trip to the countryside,
或者一个错放的征友广告
or a misplaced lonely hearts ad.
该你了!
Your move!
我已经向首相保证过你已经开始调查了
I've given the Prime Minister my personal assurance you're on the case.
我是在查案啊 我们都是 我们手头不正做呢嘛
I am on the case, we both are, look at us right now.
- 该死!  - 糟糕啊!
- Oh, bugger!  - Whoopsy!
处理不了破碎的心 多么有趣的暗示啊
Can't handle a broken heart. How very telling.
别贫嘴
Don't be smart.
这句话太熟悉了
That takes me back.
"别耍小聪明 夏洛克 我才是聪明的那个"
"Don't be smart, Sherlock, I'm the smart one."
我就是聪明的那个
I am the smart one.
我以前以为自己是白痴
I used to think I was an idiot.
我们都以为你是白痴 夏洛克
Both of us thought you were an idiot, Sherlock.
我们没别的事做 直到遇见别的小孩
We had nothing else to go on, until we met other children.
- 是啊 真是一个错误  - 可怕的错误 我们是怎么想的?
- Oh, yes, that was a mistake.  - Ghastly. What were they thinking of?
或许是想交朋友吧
Probably something about trying to make friends.
没错 朋友
Oh, yes. Friends.
当然 你现在也开始交朋友了
Of course, you go in for that sort of thing now.
你没有吗? 从来没有?
And you don't? Ever?
你可真是愚钝了 夏洛克
If you seem slow to me, Sherlock,
你能想象现实中的人是什么样子吗?
can you imagine what real people are like?
我住在一个充满蠢人的世界里
I'm living in a world of goldfish.
我知道 但我离开两年了
Yes, but I've been away for two years.
- 所以呢?  - 这个说不好
- So?  - Oh, I don't know,
我以为你或许给自己找了一个...
I thought perhaps you might have found yourself a...
- 蠢人  - 改变话题 马上
- goldfish.  - Change the subject, now.
放心吧 迈克罗夫特
Rest assured, Mycroft,
不管你的这个地下组织想干什么
whatever this underground network of yours is up to,
这个秘密都隐藏在一些看起来不起眼或者奇怪的事情上
the secret will reside in something seemingly insignificant or bizarre.
- 打扰  - 曹操到了...
- Ooh-ooh.  - Speaking of which...
我不敢相信 我就是不敢相信!
I can't believe it. I just can't believe it!
他又坐在自己的椅子上了
Him sitting in his chair again.
真是太美好了 对吧 福尔摩斯先生?
Oh, isn't it wonderful, Mr Holmes?
- 我快抑制不住激动之情了!  - 哦 他抑制地非常好
- I can barely contain myself!  - Oh, he really can, you know.
虽然表面上淡然 他私下里很开心见到你的
He's secretly pleased to see you, underneath all that.
抱歉 你指的是谁?
Sorry, which of us?
你们两个
Both of you.
我们玩点别的吧
Let's play something different.
我们怎么能玩游戏?!
Why are we playing games?!
伦敦的恐怖警告已经升级到紧急戒备了
London's terror alert has been raised to critical,
我只是在打发时间
I'm just passing the time.
我们玩逻辑演绎吧
Let's do deductions.
一个客户在我离开时留下的 你都猜到什么?
Client left this while I was out, what do you reckon?
我很忙
I'm busy.
玩会儿嘛 好久没玩过了
Oh, go on, it's been an age.
- 我总是赢  - 所以你抵抗不了诱惑
- I always win.  - Which is why you can't resist.
这没什么诱惑的 只是一个经常旅行的焦虑的
I find nothing irresistible in the hat of a well-travelled anxious,
多愁善感的不健康的有着严重口臭的墨守成规人的帽子而已
sentimental, unfit creature of habit with appalling halitosis.
- 搞定  - 也很孤僻 你不觉得吗?
- Damn.  - Isolated too, don't you think?
他为什么孤僻呢?
Why would he be isolated?
- "他?"  - 显然
- "He?"  - Obviously.
为什么? 就因为帽子的尺寸?
Why? Size of the hat?
别傻了 有的女人头也很大
Don't be silly. Some women have large heads too.
不是 他最近才剪的头发
No, he's recently had his hair cut,
你可以看到碎头发粘在里面的汗渍上
you can see the little hairs adhering to the perspiration stains on the inside.
有的女人头发也很短
Some women have short hair too.
- 极有可能  - 虽然你没跟短发女人说过话 甚至没跟女人说过话
- Balance of probability.  - Not that you've ever spoken to a woman with short hair, or, you know, a woman.
污点证明他身体不适 他很多愁善感
Stains show he's out of condition. He's sentimental cos the hat
- 因为帽子被修补过三四...  - 五次 手工精细
- has been repaired, three, four...  - Five times. Very neatly.
修理的花费超过帽子本身 是他的情感依托 还不止如此
The cost of the repairs exceeds that of the hat, he's mawkishly attached to it. More than that.
一两次修补表明多愁善感 但五次就是强迫症的表现 超级强迫症
One or two patches would indicate sentimentality. But five, five's obsessive behaviour. Obsessive compulsive.
不准吧 你的客户可是把帽子落下了
Hardly. Your client left it behind.
哪个强迫症患者会落下帽子?
What sort of an obsessive compulsive would do that?
最早的补丁已经被晒得大部分脱色了
The earlier patches are extensively sun bleached,
所以他戴着出国了 去了秘鲁
so he's worn it abroad, in Peru.
- 秘鲁?  - 这是带耳扇的毛线帽
- Peru?  - This is a chullo.
经典的安第斯帽子 羊驼毛线织成
The classic headgear of Andes, it's made of alpaca.
- 不是  - 不是?
- No.  - No?
冰岛绵羊毛 如果你懂行的话
Icelandic sheep wool. Similar, but very distinctive,
就知道很像但与众不同 我写过一篇博客介绍
if you know what you're looking for. I've written a blog on the varying
不同天然纤维各异的抗张强度
tensile strengths of different natural fibres.
我相信你们很需要这个!
I'm sure there's a crying need for that!
- 你说他很焦虑?  - 左边的棉球被咬得很严重
- You said he was anxious?  - The bobble on the left side has been badly chewed,
说明他是个神经质的人 但是...
which shows he's a man of a nervous disposition, but...
但也是个墨守成规的人
But also a creature of habit,
- 因为他没有咬右边的那个  - 一点不错
- cos he hasn't chewed the bobble on the right.  - Precisely.
闻一下经常被咬的棉球就知道他的口气了
A sniff of the offending bobble tells us all we need to know about the state of his breath.
- 厉害啊!  - 基本演绎
- Brilliant!  - Elementary.
但你忽视了他的孤僻
But you've missed his isolation.
我没看出来
I don't see it.
- 显而易见  - 哪里?
- Plain as day.  - Where?
- 昭然若揭  - 告诉我
- There for all to see.  - Tell me.
- 一清二...  - 告诉我!
- Plain as the nose on your...  - Tell me!
任何会戴这么愚蠢帽子的人
Well, anybody who wears a hat as stupid as this
都不会善于和别人交往 不是吗?
isn't in the habit of hanging around other people, is he?
不一定 或许他只是不介意与众不同
Not at all. Maybe he just doesn't mind being different.
他没必要就得是孤僻
He doesn't necessarily have to be isolated.
没错
Exactly.
你说什么?
I'm sorry?
他与众不同 那又怎样? 他为什么要介意?
He's different, so what? Why would he mind?
你说得很对
You're quite right.
别人为什么要介意呢?
Why would anyone mind?
我并不孤单 夏洛克
I am not lonely, Sherlock.
你怎么知道呢?
How would you know?
好吧 不介意的话我就回去工作了 早上好
Yes. Back to work, if you don't mind. Good morning.
没错 我也接着工作
Right, back to work.
萨默森先生
Mr. Summerson.
- 没错  - 隐睾症检查
- Right.  - Undescended testicle.
好的
Right.
- 夏洛克?  - 嗯?
- Sherlock?  - Hmm?
和约翰谈谈
Talk to John.
我已经试着跟他谈过了 他的态度非常明确
I've tried talking to him. He made his position quite clear.
放松 萨默森先生
Just relax, Mr Summerson.
他说什么?
What did he say?
- 滚...  - 咳
- F...  - Cough.
天啊
Oh, dear.
喂?
Hi?
瑞文斯太太 鹅口疮
Mrs Reeves. Thrush.
好的
Right.
你想要见我?
You wanted to see me?
是的 茉莉...
Yes. Molly...
- 嗯?  - 你想要...?
- Yes?  - Would you...?
你想要...
Would you like to...
- 共进晚餐吗?  - 一起破案吗?
- Have dinner?  - Solve crimes?
呃...
Um...
没什么不好意思的 瑞文斯太太
Absolutely nothing to be ashamed of, Mrs Reeves.
这很常见 我推荐一个疗程的...
It's very common, but I'm recommending a course of...
猴腺 普斯布瑞教授的案子就到这
Monkey glands, but enough about Professor Presbury.
哈克德先生 说说你的案子
Tell us more about your case, Mr Harcourt.
- 你确定?  - 绝对肯定
- You sure about this?  - Absolutely.
- 我需要纪录吗?  - 如果能让你好受点你就记吧
- Should I be making notes?  - If it makes you feel better.
约翰说他就是这么干的
That's what John says he does.
- 所以如果我是代替约翰...  - 你不是约翰 你是你自己
- So if I'm being John...  - You're not being John, you're being yourself.
除了我和海伦 没有人
Well, absolutely no one should have been able to empty
可以取走那账户里的钱
that bank account other than myself and Helen.
- 你为什么不认为是你的妻子干的?  - 因为我充分信任她
- Why didn't you assume it was your wife?  - Because I've always had total faith in her.
不 因为是你取走了钱 减肥中 染过发 注射过肉毒素 有外遇
No, it's because you emptied it. Weight-loss, hair dye, Botox, affair.
找律师去吧 下一个!
Lawyer. Next!
布雷克先生 痔疮
This is Mr Blake. Piles.
你好 布雷克先生
Mr Blake, hi.
你的笔友突然不来信了 是吗?
And your pen-pal's emails just stopped, did they?
你觉得他就是那个人?
And you really thought he was the one, didn't you?
是你的真爱?
The love of your life?
继父伪装成网络男友
Stepfather posing as on-line boyfriend.
什么?
What?
突然停止 让她心碎
Breaks it off, breaks her heart.
她放弃念想 乖乖在家
She swears off relationships, stays at home.
他还能得到她的薪水
He still has her wage coming in.
温迪班克先生 你是个彻头彻尾的...
Mr Windibank, you have been a complete and utter...
尿壶
Piss pot.
不用担心 注射一点就好
It's nothing to worry about, just a small infection, by the sound of it.
通常是维纳先生给你看病?
Dr Verner is your usual GP, yes?
是的 是的 从小到大都是他照顾我的
Yeah, yeah, yeah. He looked after me man and boy.
我在教堂街上开了家小店
I run a little shop just on the corner of Church Street.
卖杂志和DVD光盘
Oh. Magazines and DVDs.
我带了些你可能会感兴趣的美女哦...
I've brought along a few little beauties that might interest you...
"三个打炮手" 这是个尤物 非常色情
"Tree Worshippers." Oh, that's a corker. It's very saucy.
还有"英伦小鸟" 同样的东西
And "British Birds." Same sort of thing.
我不用 谢谢
I'm fine, thanks.
"圣战"
"The Holy War."
我知道听起来很无趣
Sounds a bit dry, I know,
有一个修女她身上的洞都...
but there's a nun with all these holes in her habit...
天啊! 夏洛克
Jesus! Sherlock.
- 什么?  - 你要干什么?
- What?  - What do you want?
什么?
Uh?
你来折磨我的吗?
Have you come to torment me?
- 你在说什么?  - 你在说什么...?
- What are you talking about?  - What are you talking...?
你觉得我会被这愚蠢的胡子给骗了吗?
What, do you think I'm going to be fooled by this bloody beard?!
你疯了! 不 不 不
You're crazy! No, no, no, no, no.
伪装不是你擅长的嘛! 这可不像你的法语
It's not as good as your French! Not as good as your French.
伪装得真差劲 夏洛克!
It's not even a good disguise, Sherlock!
你从哪弄的这些东西 玩笑商店吗...?!
Where did you get it from, a bloody joke shop...?!
天啊!
Oh, my God!
非常对不起
I, I am so sorry.
天啊!
Oh, my God!
请原谅...
Please...
没事
It's fine.
我们对这案子毫无头绪
This one's got us all baffled.
我毫不怀疑
Hmm, I don't doubt it.
(松木?)
(云杉?)
(雪松)
(新的樟脑丸)
(炭灰)
(烧伤)
怎么了?
What is it?
你发现了线索 对吧?
You're onto something, aren't you?
也许吧
Maybe.
(炫耀)
- 闭嘴 约翰  - 什么?
- Shut up, John.  - What?
没事
Nothing.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hello.  - Hmm.
- 你确定吗?  - 我确定
- Are you sure?  - I'm sure.
好的
OK.
见卡斯要迟到了 一会儿见
I'm late for Cath. I'll see you later.
- 拜  - 拜
- Bye.  - Bye.
这就是你的新搭档?
This going to be your new arrangement, is it?
让她试试
Just giving it a go.
好吧
Right.
那约翰呢?
So, John?
形同陌路了
Not really in the picture any more.
是地铁吗?
Trains?
是的
Trains.
男性 四十到五十岁之间 抱歉 你想...?
Male, 40 to 50. Oh, sorry, did you want to be...?
没 请随意
Er, no, please, be my guest.
闭嘴!  (嫉妒了?)
Shut up!
这说不通啊
It doesn't make sense.
怎么说不通?
What doesn't?
这个骨架形成时间绝不会超过...
This skeleton, it can't be any more than...
六个月
six months old.
(我 怎么做到的)
(开膛手杰克 著)
哇!
Wow!
"我怎么做到的 开膛手杰克 著"
"How I Did It, by Jack the Ripper."
- 是啊  - 这不可能
- Uh-huh.  - That's impossible.
欢迎来到我的世界
Welcome to my world.
(装逼)
我不想解释 怕侮辱你的智商
I won't insult your intelligence by explaining it to you.
不用 你随便侮辱
No, please, insult away.
(你忘了竖衣领)
这具尸体是六个月前的
The corpse is, is six months old.
穿着从博物馆里拿出来的低劣维多利亚时代的外套
It's dressed in a shoddy Victorian outfit from a museum.
赝品展出了很多年
It's been displayed on a dummy for many years,
尸体面朝东南 从织物的褪色就看得出来
in a case facing south-east, judging from the fading of the fabric.
在一场火灾之后被变卖了
It was sold off in a fire damage sale a week ago.
所以整件事是假的?
So the whole thing was a fake?
是的
Yes.
看上去那么完美
Looked so promising.
如此手到擒来
Facile.
为什么有人会费心做这些?
Why would someone go to all that trouble?
为什么呢 约翰?
Why indeed, John?
小心空隙 小心空隙
Mind the gap. Mind the gap.
谢谢替我拿过来
Oh. Thanks for hanging onto it.
不客气
No problem.
有什么事 史洛克先生?
So, what's this all about, Mr Shilcott?
我女朋友是你的粉丝
My girlfriend's a big fan of yours.
女朋友?!
Girlfriend?!
抱歉 请继续
Sorry. Do go on.
我喜欢地铁
I like trains.
- 然后...  - 我在地铁公司工作 区域线上
- Yes...  - I work on the Tube, on the District Line, and part of my job
我的部分工作是看完后抹掉监控录像
is to wipe the security footage after it's been cleared.
我浏览时 发现一个奇怪的东西
I was just whizzing through and I found something a bit bizarre.
这是一个星期前
Now, this was a week ago.
星期五晚上的最后一班车 威斯敏斯特地铁站
The last train on the Friday night, Westminster Station.
这个男人走进最后一节车
Now, this man gets into the last car.
- 车?  - 他们叫车 不是车厢
- Car?  - They're cars, not carriages.
这是地铁系统美国早期留下的名称
It's a legacy of the early American involvement in the Tube system.
他说他喜欢地铁
He said he liked trains.
下一站 圣詹姆斯公园站
And the next stop, St James' Park Station.
然后...
And...
我觉得你会喜欢的
I thought you'd like it.
他在威斯敏斯特上的最后一节车 唯一一个乘客
He gets into the last car at Westminster. The only passenger.
但到圣詹姆斯公园站的时候车就空了
And the car is empty at St James's Park Station.
解释一下 福尔摩斯先生
Explain that, Mr Holmes.
- 他可能跳车了?  - 有安全系统防止门
- Couldn't he have just jumped off?  - There's a safety mechanism that prevents the doors
在行驶途中被打开 而且还有一点
from opening in transit. But there's something else,
那列车的驾驶员从那以后就没再上班过
the driver of that train hasn't been to work since.
他的室友说他去度假了 突然发了横财
According to his flatmate, he's on holiday. Came into some money.
被收买?
Bought off?
嗯?
Hmm?
那么就是那位列车驾驶员在中途
So if the driver of the train was in on it,
让这位乘客下车的
then the passenger did get off.
中途下车也没地方去 这条线上没有停靠点
There's nowhere he could go. It's a straight run on the District Line between the two stations.
中途的隧道也没有维修出口
There's no side tunnels, no maintenance tunnels.
地图上没有任何出口
Nothing on any map. Nothing.
地铁没有停靠 但一名乘客消失了
Train never stops and a man vanishes.
很棒 对吧?
Good, innit?
我认识这个人
I know that face.
不好意思
Excuse you.
这两站之间一般情况需要五分钟
The journey between those stations usually takes five minutes
但录像那段却花了十分钟到达 十分钟从威斯敏斯特到圣詹姆士公园
and that one took ten. Ten minutes to get from Westminster to St James's Park.
我需要地图 很多张 旧地图 所有都要
I'll need maps, lots of maps. Older maps, all the maps. Right.
- 想吃点薯条吗?  - 什么?
- Fancy some chips?  - What?
我知道在马里波恩路边有个鱼薯店很不错
I know a fantastic fish shop just off the Marylebone Road,
老板每次都会多给我一些
the owner always gives me extra portions.
你是不是让他摆脱了什么谋杀罪名?
Did you get him off a murder charge?
不 我曾帮他搬货物
No, I helped him put up some shelves.
- 夏洛克?  - 嗯?
- Sherlock?  - Hmm?
- 今天为什么对我这么好?  - 报答你
- What was today about?  - Saying thank you.
为什么?
For what?
- 为你所做的一切  - 没关系的 举手之劳而已
- For everything you did for me.  - It's OK. It's my pleasure.
我是认真的
No. I mean it.
我不是说高兴 我想说没关系的
I don't mean pleasure, I mean I didn't mind.
- 我想...  - 莫里亚蒂他疏忽了 犯了致命错误
- I wanted to...  - Moriarty slipped up, he made a mistake.
因为那个对我最为重要的人 他却认为
Because the one person he thought didn't matter at all to me
对我无关紧要
was the one person that mattered the most.
是你让我成功的
You made it all possible.
但你不能再做一次了 对吧?
But you can't do this again, can you?
我今天过得很愉快 我也很想去 可惜...
I've had a lovely day. I'd love to, I just, um...
嗯 顺便祝贺你
Hmm, congratulations, by the way.
不是工作上认识的
He's not from work.
我们是通过朋友介绍的 很老套的方法
We met through friends, old-fashioned way.
他很不错 我们养了条狗 我们周末经常去酒吧
He's nice, we've got a dog, we, we go to the pub on weekends
而且我也见过他的父母 亲戚
and I've met his mum and dad and his friends and all his family.
我不清楚为什么我会跟你说这些...
I've no idea why I'm telling you any of this...
我希望你过的幸福 茉莉·琥珀
I hope you'll be very happy, Molly Hooper.
这是你应得的
You deserve it.
看来并不是你喜欢的每个男人都是反动分子
After all, not all the men you fall for can turn out to be sociopaths.
- 不是吗?  - 不是
- No?  - No.
也许我就喜欢这类型呢
Maybe it's just my type.
(选择吧! 救约翰华生还是詹姆斯·华生?)
(多还是少?)
(选择圣人或是罪人?)
(詹姆斯还是华生?)
哈德森太太 我觉得有人绑架了约翰 约翰·华生?
Oh, Mrs Hudson, sorry, I think someone's got John. John Watson?
等下 你是谁?!
Hang on, who are you?!
我是他的未婚妻
Oh, I'm his fiancee.
玛丽?
Oh. Mary?
怎么了?
What's wrong?
有个人给我发了条短信
Someone sent me this.
一开始我以为是圣经里的内容
At first I thought it was just a Bible thing,
你知道的 垃圾广告 但不是的
you know, spam, but it's not.
是跳步码
It's a skip code.
先是第一个词 然后每隔三个词
First word, then every third.
"救救约翰·华生"
"Save John Watson."
(圣詹姆斯)
现在!
Now!
我们去哪儿?
Where are we going?
圣詹姆斯 是个教堂 开车20分钟
St James The Less, it's a church. 20 minutes by car.
- 你开车来的?  - 是的
- Did you drive here?  - Er, yes.
太慢了 太慢了
It's too slow, it's too slow.
小心! 我们在等什么?!
Watch out! What are we waiting for?!
这个
This.
(估计到达教堂时间: 10分钟)
(加把劲 福尔摩斯先生 你还有十分钟)
什么意思?
What does it mean?
他们要对他做什么?
What are they going to do to him?
我不知道!
I don't know!
(还剩八分钟 倒计时...)
该死!
Damn!
喂! 喂! 你不能从那里过!
Oi! Oi! You can't go down there!
(最好快点 这里越来越热闹了...)
不行 点不着 这样点不着
No, it's not going to work, with that.
- 我去找点助燃的东西  - 好的
- I'll get something to help it along.  - Yeah.
救命! 啊!
Help! Argh!
(静候行刑 延长2分钟)
(预计到达时间: 3分钟)
(预计到达时间: 1分钟)
- 他不喜欢被烧 爸爸  - 啊?
- He doesn't like it, Daddy.  - Huh?
盖伊·福克斯 他不喜欢被烧
Guy Fawkes, he doesn't like it.
退后 佐伊 退后!
Stay back, Zoe. Back!
快点
Now.
(真遗憾 福尔摩斯先生 约翰变成了盖伊!)
这什么意思?
What does it mean?
天啊!
Oh, my God!
救命!
Help!
退后!
Stand back!
闪开! 闪开! 闪开!
Move! Move! Move!
闪开! 闪开!
Move! Move!
约翰! 约翰!
John! John!
起来 约翰!
Get up, John!
- 约翰!  - 约翰?!
- John!  - John?!
救命!
Help!
约翰!
John!
约翰! 约翰!
John! John!
- 嘿 约翰  - 约翰
- Hey, John.  - John.
我没把它放在那里 笨女人
Which wasn't the way I'd put it at all. Silly woman.
不管怎样 就是那时我第一次注意到它丢了
Anyway, it was then that I first noticed it was missing.
我问他 "你检查沙发靠背夹缝了吗?"
I said, "Have you checked down the back of the sofa?"
他总是把东西丢在沙发靠背夹缝里 是吧 亲爱的?
He's always losing things down the back of the sofa, aren't you, dear?
恐怕是的
Afraid so.
像钥匙 零钱 糖果
Oh, keys, small change, sweeties.
- 尤其是他的眼镜  - 眼镜
- Especially his glasses.  - Glasses.
特别麻烦 我说 "为什么不找根链子
Blooming things. I said, "Why don't you get a chain,
把眼镜挂脖子上?"
wear them round your neck?"
- 他回答说 "什么 就像拉里·格雷森一样!"  - 拉里·格雷森
- And he says, "What, like Larry Grayson!"  - Larry Grayson.
这么说你最后找到彩票了吗?
So did you find it eventually, your lottery ticket?
没错 谢天谢地
Well, yes, thank goodness.
我们总算准时上了大巴
We caught the coach on time after all.
我们去看了圣保罗大教堂 伦敦塔
We managed to see St Paul's, the Tower,
但他们不让任何人进议会大厦
but they weren't letting anyone into Parliament.
好像在举行什么大辩论会
Some big debate going on.
- 约翰?  - 不好意思 你在忙
- John?  - Sorry, you're busy.
不 没有 没有 他们正打算走
No, no, no, they were just leaving.
- 没有 是吗?  - 没错
- No, oh, were we?  - Yes.
别 别 如果你有案子...
No, no, if you've got a case...
- 不 不是案子 对 快走  - 要记得 我们一直待到周六
- No, not a case. Yeah, go.  - We're here till Saturday, remember.
好 很好 快走吧!
Yes, wonderful. Just get out!
- 好吧 给我们打电话  - 很好 我会的 出去吧!
- Yes, well, give us a ring.  - Very nice, yes, good. Get out!
我们真的特别开心 夏洛克
I can't tell you how glad we are, Sherlock.
那段时候人们总是想着你已经死了
All that time people thinking the worst.
一切都结束了 我们觉得特别高兴
We're just so pleased it's all over.
多打电话过来 好吗?
Ring up more often, won't you?
- 嗯  - 她很担心
- Mm-hm.  - She worries.
你保证?
Promise?
我保证
Promise.
天啊...
Oh, for God...
- 不好意思  - 没关系
- Sorry about that.  - No, it's fine.
客户?
Clients?
我父母而已
Just my parents.
- 你父母?  - 来城里玩几天
- Your parents?  - In town for a few days.
- 真的是你父母?  - 迈克罗夫特答应带他们去看悲惨世界音乐会
- Your parents?  - Mycroft promised to take them to a matinee of Les Mis.
想让我也一起去
Tried to talk me into doing it.
- 那真是你的父母?  - 没错
- Those were your parents?  - Yes.
好吧...
Well...
不是我...
that is not what I...
什么?
What?
我是说 他们好...
I mean, they're just so...
普通
ordinary.
这就是我不得不背负的十字架
It's a cross I have to bear.
他们也知道吗?
Did they know too?
- 什么?  - 你花了两年的时间玩捉迷藏?
- Hmm?  - That you spent the last two years playing hide and seek?
- 也许吧  - 所以他们才没来参加葬礼!
- Maybe.  - Ah, so that's why they weren't at the funeral!
- 对不起 真的很抱歉  - 嗯
- Sorry, sorry again.  - Hmm.
对不起
Sorry.
你把胡子刮掉了?
So you've shaved it off then?
是啊 不适合我
Yeah. Wasn't working for me.
- 确实 现在这样比较好  - 你不喜欢我原来的胡子?
- Yeah, I'm glad.  - You didn't like it?
不喜欢 我希望给我看病的医生都把胡子刮得干干净净
No, I prefer my doctors clean-shaven.
我可不是每天都听到病人这么说
That's not a sentence you hear every day.
现在感觉怎么样?
How are you feeling?
挺好的 有点被烟呛到了
Yeah, not bad. Bit smoked.
没错
Right.
昨晚是谁干的?
Last night, who did that?
他们为什么要针对我?
And why did they target me?
我不知道
I don't know.
是不是有人想通过我找到你?
Is it someone trying to get to you through me?
跟你说的恐怖分子那事有关系吗?
Is it something to do with this terrorist thing you talked about?
我也不知道 看不清这事的性质 很多线索不清楚
I don't know, I can't see the pattern. It's too nebulous.
为什么一个探员会牺牲他的性命来告诉我们一个完全不重要的情报? 这太奇怪了
Why would an agent give his life to tell us something incredibly insignificant? That's what's strange.
- 牺牲了性命?  - 迈克罗夫特是这么说的
- Give his life?  - According to Mycroft.
有个秘密组织正密谋袭击伦敦 我们现在只知道这么多
There's an underground network planning an attack on London, that's all we know.
- 这些都是我的老鼠 约翰  - 老鼠?
- These are my rats, John.  - Rats?
他们都是我的线索 有探员 有社会下层的人 都是些
My markers, agents, lowlifes, people who might find themselves
突然会被逮捕或者突然被撤销外交豁免权的人
arrested or their diplomatic immunity suddenly rescinded.
如果其中一人有可疑的行径 我们就知道出事了
If one of them starts acting suspiciously, we know something's up.
他们其中的五个表现得特别正常 但是第六个人...
Five of them are behaving perfectly normally, but the sixth...
我是不是认识他?
I know him, don't I?
上议院莫兰议员 世袭贵族 海外发展部的部长
Lord Moran, Peer of the Realm. Minister for Overseas Development.
- 国家建设的栋梁  - 就是他啊
- Pillar of the Establishment.  - Yes.
从1996年开始他就为朝鲜工作
He's been working for North Korea since 1996.
- 什么?  - 他就是只大老鼠 老鼠一号
- What?  - He's the big rat, rat number one.
他不久前的行为 特别可疑
He's just done something very suspicious indeed.
是啊 确实奇怪
Yeah, that's odd.
他真的没法在中途下车吗?
There's nowhere he could have got off?
从地图上看是这样
Not according to the maps.
肯定有原因 肯定有东西我没有想到
There's something, something, something I'm missing.
显而易见的东西 我却没看到它
Something staring me in the face.
知不知道这个地下组织都是些什么人?
Any idea who they are, this underground network?
情报组织肯定列了份嫌疑人名单
Intelligence must have a list of the most obvious ones.
我们的老鼠刚刚钻出了地洞
Our rat's just come out of his den.
会不会是基地组织? 爱尔兰共和军又开始焦躁不安了
Al-Qaeda? The IRA have been getting restless again,
- 也许那些恐怖分子准备现身...  - 没错 没错 没错 我明白了!
- maybe they're going to make an appearance...  - Yes, yes, yes, yes!
我真是个傻瓜 超级大傻瓜!
I've been an idiot, a blind idiot!
- 怎么了?  - 太棒了 真的是太聪明了!
- What?  - Oh, that's good. That could be brilliant!
- 你都想到了什么?  - 迈克罗夫特收到的情报一点也不模糊
- What are you on about?  - Mycroft's intelligence is not nebulous at all,
反而是太清晰了 难以置信地清晰
it's specific, incredibly specific.
到底什么意思?
What do you mean?
他们不是地下组织 华生 他们是地下的组织!
It's not an underground network, John, it's an Underground network!
显然如此
Right.
- 等等 什么?  - 有时候呈现给你的假象会特别放肆 特别不可理解
- What?  - Sometimes a deception is so audacious, so outrageous
以至于合理的解释就摆在你面前 你却看不见它 看这
that you can't see it even when it's staring you in the face. Look,
- 七节车厢离开了威斯敏斯特站台  - 嗯
- seven carriages leave Westminster.  - Mm.
但到达圣詹姆斯站时只有六节车厢了
And only six carriages arrive at St James's Park.
我是说 这根本不可能啊
Ah, but that's, I mean, it's impossible.
莫兰并没有消失 是整个车厢消失了
Moran didn't disappear. The entire tube compartment did.
地铁司机肯定调转了车的方向 然后把最后一节车厢分离开了
The driver must have diverted the train and then detached the last carriage.
他能把最后一节车厢放哪? 你说了这些站台之间什么也没有
Detached it where? You said there was nothing between those stations.
地图上确实什么都没有 但是一旦你排除了其它可能的因素
Not on the maps, but once you eliminate the other factors,
剩下的一定是真相 那节车厢消失了 所以它一定在某个地方
the remaining thing must be the truth. That carriage vanished, so it must be somewhere.
但为什么呢?
But why, though?
为什么要把那节车厢分离开?
Why detach it in the first place?
车厢是在圣詹姆斯和威斯敏斯特站之间不见的
It vanishes between St James's Park and Westminster.
莫兰议员也不见了
Lord Moran vanishes.
你被绑架而且差点在篝火派对里被烧死
You're kidnapped and nearly burnt to death at a fireworks party.
日期 约翰 今天几号?
What's the date, John, today's date?
嗯? 今天是11月...
Hmm? November the...
天啊!
Oh, God!
莫兰议员 他是世袭贵族
Lord Moran, he's a Peer of the Realm.
通常他都是坐在国会大厦里
Normally he'd sit in the House.
今天晚上 议员们会召开会议 彻夜为是否通过新修订的反恐法案投票
Tonight, there's an all-night sitting to vote on the new anti-terrorism bill.
但他不会出席 今晚不会
But he won't be there, not tonight.
不会在11月5日这一天出现
Not the 5th November.
"记住 记住..."
"Remember, remember..."
"火药 叛国和阴谋!"
"Gunpowder, treason and plot!"
下面什么也没有 福尔摩斯先生 我看过了
There's nothing down there, Mr Holmes, I told you.
没有旁轨 也没有秘密车站
No sidings, no ghost stations.
肯定有 继续查
There has to be, check again.
整个区域就是新建筑和旧建筑的混杂
This whole area is a big mess of old and new stuff.
查令十字街附近有一些旧车站
Charing Cross is made up of bits of older stations,
比如特拉法尔加广场站和斯德兰德站
like Trafalgar Square, Strand.
不 这些都不是 我们查过这些地方
No, it's none of those, we've accounted for those.
圣玛格丽特街站 大桥街站 萨马特拉路站 国会街站...
St Margaret Street, Bridge Street, Sumatra Road, Parliament Street...
等等 等等 萨马特拉路站?
Hang on, hang on, Sumatra Road?
你刚刚提到了萨马特拉路站 福尔摩斯先生? 那里确实有东西
You mentioned Sumatra Road, Mr Holmes? There is something,
我就知道这名字我有印象! 对
I knew it rang a bell! Yes.
那条街下面有一个车站
There was a station down there.
那为什么地图上没有呢?
Well, why isn't it on the maps?
- 因为那个车站还没有开始使用就关闭了  - 什么?
- Because it was closed before it ever opened.  - What?
当时站台和楼梯什么的都建好了 但是整个被禁用
They built the platforms, even the staircases, but it all got tied up
因为法律上的纠纷 所以之后地面上的站台就没有继续建造了
in legal disputes and so they never built the station on the surface.
它就在威斯敏斯特宫的正下方
It's right underneath the Palace of Westminster.
所以这个废旧车站里会有什么 炸弹吗?
So what's down there, a bomb?
很多评论家均表示
With many commentators saying
支持与反对新修订的反恐法案的票数将十分接近
the vote on the Terrorism Bill will be too close to call,
议员们现在正在议院中就坐
MPs are now making their way into the Chamber for what
以决定政府称之为"本届议会最重要投票"的结果
the Government is calling "the most important vote of this Parliament."
现在连线我们的...
Over now to our...
如果我们连本国人民都开始监听
What freedoms exactly are we protecting
那我们还说什么保护自由?
if we start spying on our own people?
这是个规模空前的奥威尔式举措...
This is a Orwellian measure on a scale unprecedented...
所以那里有个炸弹 对吧? 那节车厢里装了炸弹
There's a bomb, then? The tube carriage is carrying a bomb.
- 肯定有  - 好吧
- Must be.  - Right.
- 你在干什么?  - 我在报警啊
- What are you doing?  - I'm calling the police.
什么? 不行!
What? No!
夏洛克 这不是游戏 警方应该组织议员们撤离国会大厦
Sherlock, this isn't a game, they need to evacuate Parliament.
警察只会添麻烦 他们总是这样 这样更方便 更有效率
They'll get in the way, they always do. This is cleaner, more efficient.
- 而且不合法?  - 有一点
- And illegal?  - A bit.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
跟上来了
Coming.
- 我不明白  - 你也有猜错的时候
- I don't understand.  - Well, that's a first.
它不可能在别的地方啊
There's nowhere else it could be.
噢!
Oh!
怎么了?！
What?!
- 等等 夏洛克...?  - 怎么了?
- Hang on, Sherlock...?  - What?
那个炸弹 不是会爆炸的吗?
That's, isn't it live?
我们很安全的 只要别接触轨道就好
Perfectly safe as long as we avoid touching the rails.
当然 没错 不要接触轨道 太好了!
Of course, yeah, avoid the rails. Great!
往这边走
This way.
- 你确定?  - 确定
- Are you sure?  - Sure.
哈!
Ha!
看看那个
Look at that.
- 约翰...  - 怎么?
- John...  - Hmm?
全都是爆破装置
Demolition charges.
空的 什么也没有
It's empty. There's nothing.
这不就是吗?
Isn't there?
这就是炸弹
This is the bomb.
什么?
What?
这节车厢不是藏了炸弹 整个车厢本身就是炸弹
It's not carrying explosives, the whole compartment is the bomb.
我们需要拆弹专家
We need bomb disposal.
现在时间不够了
There may not be time for that now.
那该怎么办?
So what do we do?
我不知道
I have no idea.
- 赶快想啊  - 你为什么觉得我一定知道怎么做?
- Well, think of something.  - Why do you think I know what to do?
因为你是夏洛克·福尔摩斯 你是天底下最聪明的
Cos you're Sherlock Holmes, you're as clever as it gets.
但这不等于我知道怎么拆一个大炸弹!
It doesn't mean I know how to diffuse a giant bomb!
- 那你呢?!  - 我又没当过拆弹专家 我他妈就只是个医生!
- What about you?!  - I wasn't in bomb disposal, I'm a bloody doctor!
还是个士兵 你不是一直强调这一点吗!
And a soldier, as you keep reminding us all!
我们... 我们就不能直接把计时器扯掉之类的吗?
Can't... can't we rip the timer off, or something?
- 那会引爆的  - 看 我就说你懂的!
- That would set it off.  - You see, you know things!
噢!
Oh!
- 呃...  - 天啊!
- Er...  - My God!
呃...
Er...
你刚才为什么不报警?!
Why didn't you call the police?!
- 你就不能...?  - 你为什么从来不报警?!
- Can you just...?  - Why do you never call the police?!
现在说这些都晚了
Well, it's no use now.
这么说你不懂拆弹?!
So you can't switch the bomb off?!
你明明不懂拆弹 你刚才还死活不报警!
You can't switch the bomb off and you didn't call the police!
快走 约翰 马上走!
Go, John. Go now!
现在还有什么用 不是吗 时间根本不够
There's no point now, is there, because there's not enough time
如果我们不能把炸弹拆掉 其他人也会死!
to get away and if we don't do this, other people will die!
思维殿堂!
Mind palace!
- 嗯?  - 用你的思维殿堂!
- Hmm?  - Use your mind palace!
那有什么用?
How will that help?
你把世界上所有知识都放在了里面!
You've salted away every fact under the sun!
- 你觉得我大脑里某个地方就写着"如何拆弹"?  - 没错!
- And you think I've just got "how to defuse a bomb" tucked away in there somewhere?  - Yes!
有可能
Maybe.
快想!
Think!
想一想 认真想想
Think, please think.
快想!
Think!
我想不出来!
I can't!
天啊!
Oh, my God!
完了
This is it.
嗯 呃...
Um, er...
天啊!
Oh, my God!
给我关了 天啊!
Turn that off. Oh, God!
呃 嗯 呃...
Er, um, er...
对不起
I'm sorry.
什么?
What?
我做不到 我真的做不到 约翰
I can't, I can't do it, John.
我不知道怎么拆
I don't know how.
原谅我
Forgive me.
什么?!
What?!
约翰 请原谅我
Please, John, forgive me,
我的假死带给你那么多伤痛
for all the hurt that I caused you.
- 不 不 不 你装的吧  - 不是
- No, no, no, no, no, no, this is a trick.  - No.
你他妈的肯定又是装的
Another one of your bloody tricks.
- 不是  - 你就是想让我多愁善感一次
- No.  - You're just trying to make me say something nice.
这次不是的
Not this time.
你只是装好人罢了 虽然你表现得就像...
It's just to make you look good even though you've behaved like...
我曾经祈祷你不要死
I wanted you not to be dead.
好吧 那可不是什么好愿望
Yeah, well, be careful what you wish for.
如果我没回来 你就不会站在这里...
If I hadn't come back, you wouldn't be standing there and...
你的未来仍然一片光明 和玛丽一起
you'd still have a future, with Mary.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
听着 我觉得很难开口 很难开口 说这些煽情的话
Look, I find it difficult. I find it difficult, this sort of stuff.
我知道
I know.
你是我认识的最好 最聪明的人
You are the best and the wisest man that I have ever known.
我当然会原谅你
Yes, of course I forgive you.
莫里亚蒂的犯罪网络十分庞大
The criminal network Moriarty headed was vast.
植根于各个角落 就像癌症一样 于是我们想了一个计划
Its roots were everywhere, like a cancer, so we came up with a plan.
迈克罗夫特告诉莫里亚蒂我的信息
Mycroft fed Moriarty information about me.
作为回报 莫里亚蒂就给我们一些暗示
Moriarty, in turn, gave us hints,
暗示他的犯罪网络规模
just hints as to the extent of his web.
我们放了他 让他相信他占了上风
We let him go, because it was important to let him believe
这一点很重要
he had the upper hand.
然后 我就看着莫里亚蒂
And then, I sat back and watched Moriarty
一点一点摧毁我的名声
destroy my reputation, bit by bit.
我必须让他相信他打垮了我
I had to make him believe he'd beaten me,
完全打垮了我 然后他才会对我摊牌
utterly defeated me, and then he'd show his hand.
在去屋顶之前 我们设计了13种可能方案
There were 13 likely scenarios once we were up on that roof.
每一种都严格执行 并有独立代号
Each of them were rigorously worked out and given a code name.
莫里亚蒂要毁掉的不仅仅是我的名声
It wasn't just my reputation that Moriarty needed to bury.
还有我的命
I had to die.
夏洛克!
Sherlock!
你可以逮捕我 可以折磨我
You can have me arrested, you can torture me,
你可以对我做任何你想做的事
you can do anything you like with me,
但没有事能阻止我的人扣动扳机
but nothing's going to prevent them from pulling the trigger.
你在世界上仅有的三个朋友会命丧黄泉 除非...
Your only three friends in the world will die, unless...
除非我自杀 给你的故事画上圆满的句号
Unless I kill myself and complete your story.
你得承认 那样更性感
You've got to admit that's sexier.
但我没预料到莫里亚蒂的计划
But the one thing I didn't anticipate was just how far
更疯狂 回想我们在泳池的第一次见面
Moriarty was prepared to go. I suppose that was obvious,
我想那是显而易见的
given our first meeting at the swimming pool.
他一心求死
His death wish.
啊!
Argh!
我知道我没有太多时间
I knew I didn't have long.
我联系我哥 开始执行计划
I contacted my brother, set the wheels in motion.
(拉扎勒斯计划)
然后大家就开始行动
And then everyone got to work.
(拉扎勒斯计划开始实施)
不过是个戏法
It's a trick.
变戏法而已
It's just a magic trick.
行了 别说了
All right, stop it now.
等等 就站在原处
Now, stay exactly where you are.
别动!
Don't move!
好
All right.
一直盯着我
Keep your eyes fixed on me.
拜托了 你会为我这么做吗?
Please, will you do this for me?
很关键的就是让约翰待在我指定的地点
It was vital that John stayed just where I'd put him
那样的话 他的视线就会被救护站挡住
and that way his view was blocked by the ambulance station.
夏洛克!
Sherlock!
我需要落在气垫上
I needed to hit the air-bag,
我做到了
which I did.
速度是关键
Speed was paramount.
在约翰经过救护站这段时间内
The air-bag needed to be got out of the way
我们需要移走气垫
just as John cleared the station.
但我们又需要让他看到一具尸体
But we needed him to see a body.
这时就轮到茉莉出马了
That's where Molly came out.
就像天气时钟一样 我们走这边 约翰走另一边
Like figures on a weather clock, we went one way, John went the other.
然后 我们的自行车手准时出现...
Then, our well-timed cyclist...
把约翰暂时撞晕
put John briefly out of action,
我就利用这点时间与路上的假尸体进行交换
giving me time to switch places with the corpse on the pavement.
剩下的就是化妆了
The rest was just window dressing.
最后一步 在腋窝放一颗壁球
And one final touch, a squash ball under the armpit.
形成足够的压力 暂时阻止脉搏跳动
Apply enough pressure and it momentarily cuts off the pulse.
麻烦让我过去!
Let me come through, please!
- 没事的...  - 不 他是我朋友
- It's all right...  - No, he's my friend.
- 没事的  - 不 他是我朋友
- It's all right.  - No, he's my friend.
没事的 别担心... 他是我朋友 让我过去
It's all right, it's all right... He's my friend, please.
一切都按计划进行 有条不紊
Everything was anticipated, every eventuality allowed for.
行动十分完美
It worked perfectly.
茉莉 茉莉·琥珀? 她也参与了?
Molly. Molly Hooper? She was in on it?
没错 你还记得莫里亚蒂绑架的小女孩吗?
Yes. You remember the little girl who was abducted by Moriarty?
出去!
Get out!
你以为她这么怕 是因为她以为我是绑架她的人
You assumed she reacted like that because I was her kidnapper.
但我推断莫里亚蒂肯定找了和我长得很像的人
But I deduced Moriarty must have found someone who looked
来栽赃给我 而不论这个人是谁
very like me to plant suspicion, and that that man, whoever he was,
一旦没有了利用价值 就会被马上除掉
had to be got out of the way as soon as his usefulness ended.
也就是说 在太平间某处有一具
That meant there was a corpse in the morgue somewhere
和我长得很像的尸体
that looked just like me.
这招不错
Clever.
茉莉找到了尸体 伪造了死亡证明
Molly found the body, faked the records
我捐出了备用大衣
and I provided the other coat.
我有很多一样的大衣
I've got lots of coats.
怎么对付盯着约翰的狙击手的?
What about the sniper aiming at John?
迈克罗夫特的手下在他动手之前把他拿下了
Mycroft's men intervened before he could take the shot.
我们让他"再考虑一下"
He was invited to reconsider.
成了吗?
Is it done?
很好
Good.
你的流浪汉信息网也参与了?
And your homeless network?
我说过 整条街都被封锁了
As I explained, the whole street was closed off.
就像演了一出好戏
Like a scene from a play.
很精彩 是吧?
Neat, don't you think?
嗯...
Hmm...
怎么了?
What?
我可不会那么做
Not the way I'd have done it.
是吗?
Oh, really?
- 我不是说你不够高明 但是...  - 但是什么?
- No, I'm not saying it's not clever, but...  - What?
有点... 让人失望
Bit... disappointed.
观众就是爱吹毛求疵 反正我来也不是为了赢得你的满意
Oh. Everyone's a critic. Anyway, that's not why I came.
- 不是?  - 嗯 我以为你知道我为什么而来 菲利普
- No?  - No, I think you know why I'm here, Phillip.
"我怎么做到的 开膛手杰克 著"?
"How I Did It, by Jack the Ripper"?
难道你不感兴趣吗?
Didn't you think it was intriguing?
太可怕了 你竟然觉得我对那件轰动于世的案子感兴趣
Lurid. A case so sensational you hoped I'd be interested.
但你和你的粉丝们做得有点过头了 菲利普
But you overdid it, Phillip. You and your little fan-club.
我只是问心有愧 是我害的你...
I just couldn't live with myself, knowing that I'd driven you to...
不是你 一直以来你都是对的 我没死
But you didn't. You were always right, I wasn't dead.
但现在一切都好了 是吧?
No. No, and everything's OK now, isn't it?
- 是啊  - 那就好
- Yeah.  - Yeah.
但你浪费了警察的时间
Though of course you've wasted police time.
妨碍了司法公正
Perverted the course of justice.
差点让我没能阻止大规模恐怖袭击
Risked distracting me from a massive terrorist assault that could have
以至国会被摧毁 生灵涂炭
both destroyed Parliament and caused the death of hundreds of people.
上帝! 天啊 对不起 夏洛克!
Oh, God! Oh, God, I'm sorry, Sherlock!
我对不起你
I'm so sorry.
等一下
Hang on.
说不通啊
That doesn't make sense.
你怎么知道约翰会站在那里?
How could you be sure John would stand on that exact spot?
要是他走动了怎么办?
I mean, what if he'd moved?
你们行动怎么能那么神速?
And... how did you do it all so quickly?
如果他没被自行车撞倒怎么办?
What if the bike hadn't hit him?
还有 为什么你要告诉我这些?
And anyway, why are you telling me all this?
如果那些都是真的 你打死也不会告诉我的
If you'd pulled that off, I'm the last person you'd tell the truth to!
夏洛克·福尔摩斯!
Sherlock Holmes!
- 你竟然...  - 瞧瞧你那表情!
- You...  - Oh, your face!
- 太...  - 瞧瞧你那表情!
- Utter...  - Your face!
过分了!
You!
- 这次我完胜!  - 别嘚瑟了!
- Totally had you!  - You cock!
- 我就知道! 你...  - 你说的那些话太深情了
- I knew it! I knew it! You...  - Oh, those things you said, such sweet things.
- 我不知道你那么在乎我  - 你要是敢跟别人说一个字 就等死吧...
- I never knew you cared.  - I will, I'll kill you if you ever breathe a word of this...
- 以童子军的荣誉发誓...  - 你早就知道!
- Scout's honour...  - To anyone! You knew!
早就知道怎么关掉它!
You knew how to turn it off!
这里有个开关
There's an off switch.
肯定会有开关
There's always an off switch.
没有开关的话 恐怖分子
Terrorists can get into all sorts of problems
会有很多麻烦的
unless there's an off switch.
- 那你干嘛不告诉我?!  - 我也不全是在演戏
- So why did you let me go through all that?!  - I didn't lie altogether.
我真的不知道怎么关掉这些小灯
I've absolutely no idea how to turn any of these silly little lights off.
- 而且你还报警了?  - 当然要报警
- And you did call the police?  - Of course I called the police.
这次你死定了!
I'm definitely going to kill you!
又被我气得要杀人 和两年前一模一样
Oh, please. Killing me, that's so two years ago.
夏洛克 求求你了
Sherlock, please, I beg of you.
有空的时候过来一下吧
You can take over at the interval.
抱歉 兄弟 但你答应过我了
Oh, I'm sorry, brother dear, but you made a promise.
我不会再帮你的
Nothing I can do to help.
你不明白 这对我来说事关荣誉
But you don't understand the pain of it, the horror.
来吧 快下楼 他们都在等着采访你呢
Come on, you'll have to go down, they want the story.
马上就来
In a minute.
我太高兴了 玛丽 你们定好日子了吗?
I'm really pleased, Mary. Have you set a date?
- 我们想定在五月  - 春日的婚礼
- Well, we thought May. - Ah, a spring wedding.
- 其实我们订过一次婚  - 嗯
- Well, once we've actually got engaged.  - Yeah.
- 但上次没有完成  - 嗯 我都迫不及待了
- We were interrupted last time.  - Yeah. Well, I can't wait.
你会来吧 夏洛克?
You will be there, Sherlock?
婚礼我不感兴趣
Weddings, not really my thing.
- 大家好  - 你好 茉莉
- Hello, everyone.  - Hello, Molly.
- 他是汤姆 跟大家打招呼 汤姆  - 嗨
- This is Tom. Tom, this is everyone.  - Hi.
- 嗨  - 很高兴认识你们 嗨
- Hi.  - It's really nice to meet you all. Hi.
哇! 嗨 我是约翰 很高兴认识你
Wow! Yeah, hi, I'm John, good to meet you.
- 可以走了吗?  - 嗯
- Ready?  - Ready.
来杯香槟?
Champagne?
好的
Yes.
谢谢
Thanks.
Thank you.
- 坐下吧 亲爱的  - 谢谢
- Sit down, love.  - Oh, thanks.
那...
So um...
这次是认真的?
is it serious, you two?
是的 我走出情殇了
Yeah. I've moved on.
你不...?
Did you...?
- 我可不评论  - 你最好别说
- I'm not saying a word. - No, best not.
- 你还没说完  - 什么?
- But I'm still waiting.  - Hmm?
他们为什么要杀我?
Why did they try and kill me?
调查他们的是你 被追杀的为什么是我呢?
If they knew you were onto them, why come after me?
为什么把我往火坑里推?
Put me in a bonfire?
不知道 真讨厌
I don't know. I don't like not knowing.
约翰 和你博客上被粉饰了的小说不同
Unlike the nicely embellished fictions on your blog, John,
现实生活可不是童话故事
real life is rarely so neat.
我不知道谁是幕后主使 但我会查出来的
I don't know who was behind all this, but I will find out,
相信我
I promise you.
别压抑你的兴奋了
Don't pretend you're not enjoying this.
- 什么?  - 你喜欢回来当英雄
- Hmm?  - Being back. Being a hero again.
- 别瞎说  - 你不要再自欺欺人了
- Don't be stupid.  - You'd have to be an idiot not to see it.
- 你喜欢这样  - 什么样?
- You love it.  - Love what?
当大侦探福尔摩斯
Being Sherlock Holmes.
不知道你在说什么
I don't even know what that's supposed to mean.
夏洛克 你会告诉我你是怎么做到的吧?
Sherlock, you are going to tell me how you did it?
你怎么从楼顶跳下来还毫发无损?
How you jumped off that building and survived?
你知道的 约翰 我有不死之身
You know my methods, John, I am known to be indestructible.
别开玩笑了 我是认真的
No, but seriously.
你假死之后 我去过你的墓地
When you were dead, I went to your grave.
我知道你会去
I should hope so.
我说了一些话
I made a little speech.
是对你说的
I actually spoke to you.
我在场 都听到了
I know. I was there.
我祈求奇迹能再次发生
I asked you for one more miracle.
我祈求你不要死
I asked you to stop being dead.
我听到了
I heard you.
好了 大侦探福尔摩斯该登场了
Anyway, time to go and be Sherlock Holmes.
约翰!
John!